These guidelines are a binding component of the contract between you and RapidShare AG. RapidShare AG undertakes, effective in law, to maintain this component of the contract at all times for all services and for all customers.

Is your personal data stored?

In general you can access our website without disclosing who you are.

In order that you can use the services of RapidShare, however, we request that you provide particular personal information on the registration site. During this registration you will be requested to provide contact information (e.g. your E-Mail address). This information will be used to open your account.

To improve the performance of our Services we collect selected statistical information. We use tracking services from third parties, with which and some times with help from cookies, non-personal information about the usability of our website and the usability of our services as a whole are kept track of in order to gather relevant usage data and statistical mass data.

Information relating to our services

If necessary we will send you information closely relating to our services. For example if you have changed your password. As a rule you cannot unsubscribe to such notifications, because these E-Mails are not sent for advertising purposes.

We will also communicate with you in order to inform you about services from our website in which you have expressed an interest. You can deactivate these E-Mails under my Account.

What happens with the data you have stored or transferred?

During each upload process, in addition to the data itself, the following data will be stored:

The MD5-checksum of the data (an MD5 value is generated with each saved file in RapidShare. This is a 16-character figure, which yields the same value on repeated evaluation of the same data. This value is stored with the data. If data is stored with RapidShare which infringes our terms of use, this can be identified by the MD5-value, so that the same file can no longer be uploaded). With each upload in addition the IP-address of the computer and the time of the upload, as well as the account attribution of the data are stored.

We do not open or analyse your stored data. We allow no one access to this data, we use no independent service provider in security-sensitive areas, and we work exclusively with servers in Germany and Switzerland.

The security of your personal data

The security of your personal data is very important to us. We comply with generally accepted standards for the protection of personal data transmitted to us both on transfer and after reception of this data. Nevertheless, no method of transfer via the Internet and no method of electronic storage is completely secure. As a result we cannot guarantee the absolute security of data. Should you have queries regarding the security of our website, you can contact us as follows.

Deleting your personal data

If your personal data changes or if you no longer wish to make use of our service, then you can correct, update, supplement, delete/remove or deactivate it, by making the appropriate change in your account, or contacting us via contact.

Which statutory regulations apply?

Our services take place in compliance with international legal data protection guidelines. In addition the content of the files you have transferred is subject to protection from unauthorised access by us or third parties through the regulations of Swiss law. We reserve the right to disclose your personal data if we are of the opinion that this disclosure is required in order to protect our rights and/or to comply with a lawsuit, a warrant or a legal procedure, which involves our services.

Changes to these Privacy Guidelines

We reserve the right to change this data protection statement. Therefore please take notice of messages relating to this. However the personal data you have already submitted is governed by the preceding guidelines and won’t be affected by such changes unless you agree to them. Therefore please take notice of messages relating to this.

Should we decide to change our data protection guidelines, we will publish these changes within this data protection statement on the website and other locations in order to inform you about them.
